CURRICULUM VITAE

MANOJ MAHENDRA VISHWAKARMA

M.NO:- 7738425391

Email:-manojv0001@gmail.com, manojv0001@yahoo.com

Career Objective

Though I believe that there is no limit to growth and improvement my goal is to give direction to my career. I will show my caliber, give my best in professional pursuit for overall benefit and growth of the company that I serve and gain useful experience.

Academic Qualification

| DEGREE | YEAR | UNIVERSITY | INSTITUTE | PERCENTAGE |
|--------|-------------|----------------------------|--|------------|
| B.E. | 2011 - 2015 | Mumbai University | Fr. C. Rodrigues Institute of Technology | 64 |
| HSC | 2008 – 2010 | MAHARASHTRA STATE BOARD | N.M.F.C | 57.17 |
| SSC | 2008 | MAHARASHTRA STATE BOARD | S.R.M.V | 73.23 |

Academic Projects

• Final Year Projects

Title: Human Gesture Recognition for Mouse Control

Role: Project Lead

Languages & Tools: C#, Opency 2.4.10.

${\bf Description}:$

The aim is to design interactive machanisms which are more adapted than traditionally used devices. This system is advantageous in terms of its cost effectiveness and ease of use. This project includes:

-- YCbCr filtering, Convex hull defect Technique, Background Subtraction Method.

Others Projects

• Android Projects

Title: BucketDrops

Languages: Android, Java

Description::

BucketDrops is an app that lets you set life goals and lets you mark which goals you accomplished as time elapses

• Company Android Projects

Title: Shank Global Jobs **Languages**: Android, Java

Description::

It simplifies jobseeker to apply for a job, related to their industry and interested locations.

• Title: Rockabyte

Description::

Rockabyte is an entertainment app with never before seen features. It's a unique interactive platform for every individual to promote them self in the eyes of the world. While fulfilling your needs of entertainment at constrained times; Rockabyte presents exclusive video content in different categories with no hassle of selecting what you wish to see from thousands of streaming videos like other platforms.

Technical Skills

- **Domain (Mobile Application)**: Android Application Development.
- Operating Systems : Linux (Ubuntu), Windows 7/8/10.
- Languages : Java, JSP, Servlets, JDBC
- Technologies: Android, HTML, CSS, Javascript, AngularJS, Ionic Framework
- Database : MySQL, SQL

Work Experience

| Organization | Designation | Working period | |
|---------------------------|-----------------------|--------------------------|--|
| Internship | Android Developer | 3 months | |
| Think Technology Services | Jr. Android Developer | July 2016 - October 2017 | |
| Paras Cadd Pvt Ltd | Android Developer | Nov 2016 – Mar 2018 | |
| Bonanza Portfolio Ltd | Android Developer | Mar 2018 - Present | |

Curriculum Activities

- Was a member of college STUDENT COUNCIL during the academic year 2012-2013
- Organised intra-collegiate cultural and sports festival FACES 2012
- Organised inter-collegiate festival ETAMAX 2013 including various cultural as well as technical Workshops, Seminars and Competitions

Achievements

 Participated in the International Conference on Computational Intelligence Applications (ICCIA - 2015) and presented / published a paper entitled "Human Gesture Recognition for Mouse Control" held during February 25-27,2015 at Sandip Foundation, SITRC, Nashik (Maharashtra), India.

Strengths

- Good Team Player and Keen Learner.
- Dedicated, disciplined and believe in teamwork.
- Committed to deadlines and schedules.
- Strive for Perfection in every work.

Personal Details

Father's name :- Mahendra Vishwakarma
Date of Birth :- 3rd November,1991

Marital Status :- Single
Gender :- Male
Nationality :- Indian

Languages Known
Address
English, Hindi, Marathi
Kandivali (E), Mumbai

• Interests :- Playing Cricket, Chess & listening soft music

I hereby declare that above information is true to the best of my knowledge & belief.

Place: MUMBAI

Date:

(MANOJ VISHWAKARMA)